因为每次我看见你的脸
'Cause every time I see your face
就情不自禁地失态
I can't help but fall from grace
这女的很棒
This girl's good.
是啊，歌词押韵 我以前倒没想过
Yeah,a song with rhyming words! I never thought of that before.
我喜欢她
I like her.
为什么？因为她会唱歌 弹吉他，还可边弹边唱吗？
Why? Because she can both sing and play guitar at the same time?
这正是我对表演艺人的期待
That's all I'm looking for from these people.
看，你忌妒得要命
Look at you,all jealous.
拜托，菲比 你们俩的风格完全不同
Come on,Pheebs. You two have completely different styles.
她比较…你知道
She's more.... You know?
而你比较…
And you're more....
说你会留在我身边
Say you'll stay beside me
看到没？ 大家都很高兴她唱完了
See? Everybody else is happy she's done.
好，我接下来要唱的是…
Okay,my next song's called:
“菲比布菲，我该怎么说？ 我很怀念当初…
"Phoebe Buffay,What Can I Say? I Loved When We Were...
我们一起唱歌的日子 我不该那样离开你的”
...Singing Partners and I Shouldn't Have Left You That Way."
就是那种“寻找隐藏含义”的歌
One of those "look for the hidden meaning" songs.
本集播出：“菲比的旧搭档”
The One With Phoebe's Ex-Partner
嘿，菲比
Hey,Phoebe.
嘿，莱丝莉
Hey,Leslie.
你怎么知道我会在这里？
How'd you know I'd be here?
我在卖大鱼的地方看到佛拉德
I saw Vlad at the place where they sell the big fish.
她说你常在这里玩，所以…
He said you played here a lot,so....
我要上洗手间
I have to go to the bathroom.
如果你们又谈到“大鱼”…
If "big-fish place" comes up again...
我想知道是好几条大鱼 还是一条大鱼而已
... I'd like to know if that's several big fish or just one big fish.
菲比说你写广告歌
So Phoebe says you write jingles.
我是说她抛弃我去写广告歌
Actually,I said she abandoned me to write jingles.
有没有我们听过的？
Anything we might've heard of?
家永远不远
Home is never far away
回家的感觉就是家星跗
Home is Homestar Stew.
但我已经不写了 我有点厌倦了
But I don't do that anymore. I got kind of sick of it.
再说我也写不出好东西 所以被炒鱿鱼了
And then I couldn't come up with anything good,so they fired me.
太可惜了
Bummer.
你知道，我只是…
Well,you know,I was just....
我只是想或许…
I was just thinking and just hoping that...
也许你愿意跟我再度合作
... maybe you'd want to get back together?
不了，不过，谢谢你
No,but,thanks.
拜托，菲比 你考虑一下好吗？
Come on,Phoebe. Would you just think about it?
不了，不过，谢谢你
No,but,thanks.
再见，菲比
See you,Pheebs.
你好狠心
That was kind of brutal.
你们都要记住
Let this be a lesson to all of you.
一旦背叛我 我就成了冷血的女人
Once you betray me,I become like the lce Woman.
我是铁石心肠，绝不心软
I'm just very cold,hard,unyielding.
任何东西都无法 穿透我这冰冷的外衣
You know,nothing can penetrate this icy exterior.
给我一张面纸好吗？
Can I have a tissue?
里面有人吗？
Is someone in there?
我是在玩比大胆的游戏
I'm playing a daredevil game...
叫做“等到最后一刻 然后暴毙而死”
...called "Wait Until the Last Moment Before I Burst and Die."
老天啊，你是不是跌到…
Jeez,man! Did you fall?
嗨
Hi!
你…是兴奋过度吗？
So did you? Did you fall high?
女厕里有人，我等不及了
Someone was in the ladies' room. I couldn't wait.
不过我帮你把马桶盖掀起来了
I left the lid up for you,though.
这样吧，甘瑟，你先
You know what,Gunther? Go ahead.
我要跟这位…
I'm talking to....
这时候你要报上你的名字
This is where you say your name.
金吉儿
Ginger.
金吉儿 我在跟金吉儿说话，所以…
Ginger. I'm talking to Ginger,so...
你不必上厕所吗？
Don't you have to use the bathroom?
不，我只是… 我宁可跟你聊天
No,I just I'd rather talk to you.
是的
Yes,I do.
对，我再不上就不行了
Yes,I do have to go to the bathroom.
里面有人
There's someone in here.
钱德在哪里？ 他不能去了
-Where's Chandler? -He can't make it.
他说他要回去上班…
He said he had to go back to his job and
乔伊？
Joey?
乔伊崔比亚尼？
Joey Tribbiani?
我看得到你，好吗？
I can see you,okay?
你藏在外套后面
You're hiding behind the coats.
差点就被逮到了
Close one.
嗨
Hi.
嗨，甜心
Hi,sweetie.
嗨
Hello.
嘿，罗斯
Hey,Ross.
我有坏消息 什么坏消息？
-I've got some bad news. -What?
我可以去吃饭 但饭后要回来加班
I can eat,but I have to come back here.
拜托，你已经连续 加班两星期了
Come on. You've worked late every night for two weeks.
这次又有什么事？ 是我不好，我今天辞职了
-What is it now? -It's my fault. I quit today.
但工作重要
But work comes first!
但可惜你要走了 出了什么事？
But that's sad about you,though. What happened?
出了什么事？精力耗尽了 精力耗尽了是吗？
What happened? Burn out? Burn all out,did you?
他另有高就
He's leaving for a better job.
太好了，我想那就再见了
That's great. So I guess this is goodbye then.
再见
Goodbye.
好吧
Okay,then.
我们会想你的
Well,we're gonna miss you around here.
我也是
Yeah,me too.
星期六见 没问题
-So see you on Saturday. -Yeah,you bet!
知道吗，这个在印度是一种美味食品
Now,you know those are a delicacy in lndia.
是莱丝莉呼叫我 看我们能不能复合
That was Leslie calling to see if we can get back together.
她已经打了二十次了 祝你好运，莱丝莉
It's like the 20th time today. Yeah,good luck,Leslie.
她一定把你伤得很重
She must've hurt you bad.
是啊，我们是最好的朋友
Well,yeah. You know,we were best friends...
我们从小就是好朋友 我们的母亲是游艇上的同事
...ever since we were little. Our moms worked on the barge together.
你们两个在游艇上 跑来跑去一定很可爱
You two must've been so cute,running around on a barge.
游艇上不能跑来跑去
You never run on a barge!
钱德在吗？
Is Chandler around?
他在咖啡厅跟一个女的有约
He met some girl at the coffeehouse.
金吉儿什么的
Ginger something.
你确定不是金吉儿的谐音而已 像金洁儿什么的？
Sure it wasn't something that sounded liked Ginger? Like "Gingeer"?
不，是金吉儿
No,it was Ginger.
我之所以记得是因为 他告诉我的时候，我说
I remember because when he told me,I said:
“电影明星”
The movie star
老天
Oh,man!
我就是在躲这个女的
That's the girl I was hiding from.
要是知道他是我室友 她一定会告诉他我的事
When she sees he's my roommate,she'll tell him what I did.
你做了什么事？
What did you do?
不，我不能…
Oh,no! I can't....
我不能跟你说 我从没做过这么过分的事
I can't tell you. It's the most awful thing I've ever done.
你并没有使我们减少听故事的兴趣
You're really not making us want to hear it less.
别告诉我们
Don't tell us.
等钱德回家再说，那样更好玩
We'll wait till Chandler gets home. It'll be more fun that way.
大概是四年前
It was,like,four years ago.
金吉儿和我约了几次会 有一个周末…
Ginger and I had gone out a few times. Then one weekend...
我们到她爸爸的渡假木屋
...we went to her Dad's cabin...
只有我们两个人 和她讨厌的小狗辣椒
...just me,her and her annoying little dog,Pepper.
那天晚上 我做了一顿浪漫的烛光晚餐…
That night I cooked this really romantic dinner
你给她下毒
You gave her food poisoning!
我才想呢
I wish.
晚饭后，我们两个和辣椒 在炉火前面睡着了
After dinner,me,her and Pepper fell asleep in front of the fire.
我在半夜醒来，看到火快熄了
I woke up in the middle of the night and saw the fire was dying out...
就拿起一条木柴丢进去
...so I picked up a log and threw it on.
至少我以为那是一条木柴
Or what I thought was a log.
我的天，你把辣椒丢进火里了
Oh,my God! You threw Pepper on the fire!
我才想呢
I wish.
我应该告诉你们，金吉儿…
Another thing I probably should've told you about Ginger...
她其实…
...is that she kind of has a...
装了假腿
...artificial leg.
我的天
Oh,my God!
你把那个丢进火里？
You threw it on the fire?
她一定大发脾气
She must've freaked out.
也许吧
Yeah, she must've.
-你不知道？-嗯…
-You don't know? -Well....
你把她的腿 丢进火里之后怎么做的？
What did you do after you threw her leg on the fire?
我逃跑了
I ran!
-你跑了？ -是的，跑过树林 没有穿袜子
-You ran? -Through the woods, with no socks on.
这是我这一生最美好的吻
That's the best kiss I've had...
至少凌驾 我在男厕所遇到的其他人
...with anybody I met in a men's room.
我也是
Actually,me too.
脚踩进水坑里了
Foot all in the puddle!
要命，我最讨厌这样
Damn! I hate that!
你得把鞋子脱掉 不用紧张
-You'll have to get out of those shoes. -Don't worry.
不，真的，你会冻坏的
No,really. You're gonna freeze.
我不会
No,I'm not.
你不会，你有仿生电子脚？
You're not? Have you got a bionic foot?
也许有一天会吧
Someday. Maybe.
这本书很好笑吗？
Funny book?
我只是在想我今天听到的 一句很有意思的话
I'm just thinking about something funny I heard today.
马克说“星期六见”
Mark saying,"I'll see you Saturday."
对，我们要去听讲座
Yeah,at the lecture.
我上星期就告诉你了 你说你不介意
I told you last week. You said you didn't mind.
我不是介意那场讲座
It's not the lecture I mind.
拜托，你不是因为 我要跟马克去吧？
Please tell me it's not because I'm going with Mark.
这个嘛… 我的天
-Well -Oh,my God!
对不起 不过你们已经不是同事了
I'm sorry,but if you're not working with him anymore...
为什么还要混在一起
...why do you still hang out?
因为他是我朋友
Because he's my friend.
但你真的需要 别的“朋友”吗？
But do you really need another "friend"?
如果我不再跟乔伊和钱德玩了 可以跟马克玩吗？
If I stop playing with Joey and Chandler,can I play with Mark?
这好笑吗？我应该笑吗？
Is that funny? Am I suppose to be laughing?
我不知道，你觉得 “星期六见”很好笑
I don't know. You thought "See you Saturday" was funny.
马克也是时装业的
Mark is in fashion.
我喜欢有个可以跟我分享的朋友
I like having a friend I can share this stuff with.
你们这些男生 不肯跟我去听讲座
You guys would never go to a lecture with me.
我很愿意跟你去
I'd love to go with you.
真的？
Really?
我有衣服
I have clothes.
还是我自己挑的
I even pick them out.
告诉你，我可以当个时装…
For all you know,I could be a fashion...
摊贩
... monger.
我很希望你陪我去
I would love for you to go with me.
怎么了？
What?
我该穿什么衣服？ 这下我好紧张
What should I wear? Now I'm all nervous.
你知道，人家说 “有人看的锅子不会叫”
You know,they say "A watched pot never beeps."
已经几个小时了…
It's been a couple hours...
她还没打
...and she hasn't called.
不是说我在乎，我不在乎
Not that I even care. I don't.
你干脆打电话给她吧
Why don't you just call her?
看你就知道你很想打
You obviously want to.
你自以为很了解我
You think you know me so well.
你不想打吗？
Well,don't you wanna?
所以我是很了解你
So I do know you.
我就是这么说的
That's what I said.
怎么样？
Well,so?
我办不到
I can't.
我办不到，她抛弃了我
I can't. She dumped me.
我完全相信她 然后突然有一天
I totally trusted her,then one day it was like:
“好，再见，菲比” 一去不回
"Okay,bye,Pheebs." Gone!
你知道最叫人 难过的是什么吗？
You know what the saddest part is?
我们在一起 表演的时候，是我…
When we were playing together,that was...
一生最快乐的时光了
...the most fun I've ever had in all my lives.
我最爱的鞋子，好好穿 我每天非穿不可
My favorite shoes,so good to me I wear them every day
鞋底塌了，脚趾开口 不在乎别人怎么说
Down at the heel,holes in the toes Don't care what people say
我双脚的知音 永远的好友
My feet's best friend Pals to the end
穿着这双鞋 我就是性感小辣妹
With them,I'm one hot chickie
不过有一天晚上 天色灰暗
Though late one night Not much light
我踩到黏黏的东西
I stepped in something icky
黏黏的鞋子，黏黏的鞋子
Sticky shoes,sticky shoes
永远让我破涕为笑
Always make me smile
黏黏的鞋子，黏黏的鞋子 下次我要…
Sticky shoes,sticky shoes Next time I'll...
躲开…
...avoid the...
泥巴堆
...pile!
我们开始看到许多层的 极薄布料和颜色
We're beginning to see a lot of layering of sheer fabrics and colors.
例如，一件极薄的 海军蓝衬衫搭配一件…
For instance,a sheer navy blouse over a pink....
我很高兴我们来听
I'm really glad we came.
你好美
You're so pretty.
我爱你
I love you.
臭臭猫，臭臭猫
Smelly cat,smelly cat
他们拿什么给你吃？
What are they feeding you?
臭臭猫，臭臭猫
Smelly cat,smelly cat
这不是你的错
It's not your fault
太棒了
That's great!
这首歌可以拿去卖
You know,you could totally sell this.
非常适合用来…促销猫砂
It'd be perfect for,like,a kitty-litter campaign.
广告歌？
A jingle?
有何不可？可以赚大钱
Why not? You'd make a ton of money.
如果我是为了赚钱 早就是百万富翁了
If I was in this for the money,I'd be a millionaire by now.
你得把广告歌这种事给忘了
You gotta get out of that jingle-head.
你说得对…对不起
You're right. You're right. I'm sorry.
没关系
That's okay.
我现在要唱一首非常哀伤的歌
I'm gonna play a song now that's really,really sad.
叫做“魔术箱搞混了”
It's called "Magician Box Mix-Up."
特大号的手镯，特大号的耳环
Oversized bracelets,oversized earrings...
一般来说，特大号的配件 是今年的主流
...oversizing of accessories,in general,is very popular now.
可以借我吗？ 我的牛奶坏了
Can I borrow this? My milk's gone bad.
我不喜欢这样
I hate that.
我以前很喜欢跟人家平分 结果别人偷了我的车
I once had a thing of half-and-half. Stole my car.
你跟金吉儿的约会怎么样了？
So how was your date with Ginger?
太棒了
Great.
很棒，她…
It was great. She's....
她很棒，长得漂亮 性情好，无可挑剔
She's great. Great looks and personality. Greatness.
看样子她很…
Sounds like she's got the...
完整
...whole package.
所以她很完美？
So she's got it all, huh?
她真的是你想要的？
She's the real deal?
乔伊跟你说过那条腿的事了？
Joey told you about the leg,huh?
吓死我了
Oh,God! It freaked me out.
不应该这样才对，但这是真的
It shouldn't,but it did.
我喜欢她，想跟她交往下去 不过我忍不住…
I wanna keep seeing her,but it's like:
“嘿，说真的，你的腿呢？”
"Hey,you know what? Where's your leg?"
我是全世界最渺小的人，是吧 我是全世界最渺小的人
I'm the smallest person in the world,aren't l?
早安
Morning.
其实他才是全世界最渺小的人
Actually,he's the smallest person in the world.
听过火烧腿的事了吧
Heard about the leg-burning,huh?
她提过
It came up.
我知道机会渺茫，可是…
Listen,I know it's a long shot,but...
她觉得这件事有趣吗？
... by any chance,did she find that funny?
我是打了一下瞌睡
So I nodded off a little!
打瞌睡？ 罗斯，你还打呼
"Nodded off"? Ross,you were snoring!
我爸爸的船撞上岩石的时候 都没有这么大声
My father's boat didn't make that much noise when it hit rocks!
拜托，45分钟
Come on! Forty-five minutes....
那个人讲了45分钟的 露背吊带裙
Forty-five minutes,the man talked about strappy-backed dresses.
好，那在冰冷的博物馆礼堂 坐上四个小时…
Okay,how about four hours in a freezing museum auditorium...
听皮兹坦教授说…
...Iistening to Professor "Pitstains" say:
“记得这东西是 亿万年前死的吗？”
"Remember that thing that died a gazillion years ago?
“我们过去不知道 它有这块小骨头”
Well,here's a little bone we didn't know it had!"
首先，那是皮坦教授
First of all,it's Professor Pitain.
其次，那块小骨头证明了…
And second of all,that little bone proved that...
那只恐龙有翅膀，可是不会飞
...that particular dinosaur had wings but didn't fly.
好，你知道 我听到的是什么吗？
Okay,you know what I just heard?
一亿人跑去看一部以我的工作为主题的电影（《侏罗纪公园》）
A hundred million people went to see a movie about what I do.
我不知道有多少人会去看一部叫“侏罗纪外套”的电影
I wonder how many people would go see a movie called Jurassic Parka.
那实在是…
Oh,that is so
一群抓狂的夹克衫控制整个小岛
A bunch of out-of-control jackets take over an island!
如果我的工作这么愚蠢
If what I do is so lame...
你干嘛坚持今天早上要陪我去
...then why did you insist on coming with me this morning?
这样我就不会跟马克去吗？
Was it so I just wouldn't go with Mark?
我想跟你在一起
I wanted to be with you.
我不知道，我最近觉得…
I don't know,I feel like lately...
你离我越来越远…
...you're slipping away from me...
你有了新工作，认识了新朋友
...with this new job and all these new people.
你的人生多彩多姿
And you've got this whole other life going on.
我知道这很愚蠢
I know it's dumb...
但我痛恨不能参与你的生活
...but I just hate that I'm not a part of it.
这并不愚蠢
It's not dumb.
但也许你不能参与也不要紧
But maybe it's okay that you're not a part of it.
你懂我的意思吗？
You know what I mean?
我是说…
I mean,it's like...
我不希望你参与 我在这方面的生活
... I like that you're not involved in that part of my life.
这样就清楚一点了
That's a little clearer.
你看，这不表示我不爱你
See,it doesn't mean I don't love you...
因为我是爱你的 我非常爱你
... because I do. I love you so much.
但我的工作 是属于我的，你知道吗？
But my work It's for me,you know?
我独立自主、努力投入
I'm out there on my own,and I'm doing it.
这很可怕，但我很喜欢 因为这是属于我的
And it's scary,but I love it because it's mine.
但我是说，这样可以吧？
But I mean,is that okay?
当然
Sure.
你在想我的腿
You're thinking about my leg.
其实我已经忘了 那是怎么回事？
Actually,I forgot. What's the deal with that again?
听我说，如果你介意也不要紧
Look,it's okay if it bothers you.
我只需要知道 你介意到什么程度
I only need to know how much it bothers you...
因为我不喜欢浪费时间
...because I don't like wasting my time.
我在浪费时间吗？
Am I wasting my time?
不，我想没有
No,I don't think so.
这也没什么 只要习惯就好了
It's like anything else. You just have to get used to it.
那是什么？
What's that?
那是我的“结结”
That's my "nubbin."
结结是什么？
What's a nubbin?
就好像是第三个乳头
It's kind of a third-nipple kind of thing.
你有三个乳头？
You have three nipples?
有两个正常的…
Well,you know,two regulars...
还有一个算不上是…
...and one that barely qualifies as a
什么？
What?
没什么，我…
Nothing. You know,l....
我只是想起来，我该走了
I just remembered. I have to leave.
你要走？现在…？为什么？
You have to leave? Now? How come?
结结，不，没什么
Well,it's nubbin. Nothing!
这样吧，再联络
You know what? I'll see you later.
我还以为你不来了
I thought you weren't coming.
你到哪里去了 过来…
-Where were you? -Come here,come here.
不要生气，好吗？
Don't get mad,okay?
不要给我理由生气，好吗？
Don't give me a reason to get mad,okay?
我把“臭臭猫”唱给我以前的广告公司听，他们爱死了
I played Smelly Cat for my old ad agency. They went nuts!
我说过我不要你拿去卖
I told you I didn't want you to try and sell it...
你这个大肥猪还是做了
...and you just big,fat did it anyway!
我想五年前 我恐怕会不计一切…
I think,five years ago,I probably would have done anything...
只求能跟你一起表演
...to play with you.
但我自己还是可以唱 如果我不能信任你，就忘记吧
But I can do it myself. If I can't trust you,then forget it.
我不想忘记
I don't wanna forget it.
这样吧，你必须做个选择
You know what? You have to choose.
如果你觉得世界上最重要的…
If the most important thing on the planet to you...
是猫拉屎之类的事情 那“臭臭猫”就送给你
...is this cat-poopy thing,then you can have Smelly Cat.
但我们以后再也不是搭档
But we won't be partners.
你决定怎么样？
So what's it gonna be?
臭臭猫，臭臭猫 猫砂箱有臭味？
-Smelly cat,smelly cat -Problem odor in the litter box?
不要换你的猫 换你的猫砂
Don't change your kitty,change your kitty litter.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault
对不起，菲比
Sorry,Pheebs.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我没事
I actually am.
因为生命中会发生各种遭遇
Because,you know,life's gonna hand you all kinds of stuff.
得到教训以后，希望可以成长
You learn your little lessons and hopefully you grow.
要听新歌吗？ 太好了
-You wanna hear a new song? -We'd love to.
广告婊子又来搞我
Jingle bitch screwed me over
去死吧，广告婊子
Go to hell,jingle whore
去死吧…
Go to hell,go to hell,go to hell
我只写了这么多
That's all I have so far.
嗨
Well,hello!
你到哪里去了？ 医院
-Where you been? -The doctor.
一切都顺利吧？
Is everything okay?
只是动了结结切除术
Just had me a little nubbin-ectomy.
两个乳头，无需等待
Two nipples,no waiting.
跟瑞秋在高中的时候一样
Well! Just like Rachel in high school.
什么？
What?
拜托，我是开玩笑的 一听就知道是个笑话
Come on,I was kidding! It was such an obvious joke.
的确一听就是个笑话
That was an obvious joke.
可是我没听出来，为什么？
And I didn't think of it. Why?
我能量的来源？
The source of all my powers.
老天，我做了什么事？
Oh,dear God,what have I done?